<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loves fierce dispute. An excellent new song sung with its own proper tune.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B26278</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888236</idno>
  <idno type="VID">201016</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248541224</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L3266A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.121.g.9[46]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R229207</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888236</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888236e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B26278)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 201016)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; A8:1[46])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Loves fierce dispute. An excellent new song sung with its own proper tune.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1670]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (CD-ROM, 1996).</note>
                  <note>Two columns of text, initial.</note>
                  <note>First line: "A fierce dispute of late there was."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Ballads, English --  17th century.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Love --  England --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="song">
            <pb facs="tcp:201016:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>Loves Fierce Dispute</hi> AN EXCELLENT NEW SONG</head>
            <opener>Sung with its own proper tune,</opener>
            <lg>
               <l>A Fierce Dispute of late there was</l>
               <l>Between a young Man and a Lass;</l>
               <l>F<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> he b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>gan to Complement,</l>
               <l>Thi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> king <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>er humor to content;</l>
               <l>And with these words he did her greet</l>
               <l>Thrice welcome unto me my sweet;</l>
               <l>I pray you now before you go,</l>
               <l>If you love me, tell me so.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Kind Sir she said, I pray be mute,</l>
               <l>Break <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ff discourse and slack your sure,</l>
               <l>For I am not dispos'd at all,</l>
               <l>To come at every young Mans call:</l>
               <l>Nor sh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ll blind <hi>Cupid</hi> with his dart,</l>
               <l>Make an incision in my Heart;</l>
               <l>Therefore forbear my Company,</l>
               <l>I cannot love thee no not I.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>My love to thee is most intire,</l>
               <l>And this of thee I do desire,</l>
               <l>To speak the very truth of mind,</l>
               <l>Tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> I the truth thereof may find,</l>
               <l>And as your are a vertuous Maid,</l>
               <l>Make answer to that which <hi>I</hi> have said,</l>
               <l>Whether you are my freind or foe,</l>
               <l>If you love me tell me so.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Lass to him replyed again,</l>
               <l>I am a Maid I tell you plain,</l>
               <l>And as I am a Maid, quoth she,</l>
               <l>So take this Answer now of me,</l>
               <l>I have no Love for thee in store,</l>
               <l>Therefore I pray thee tempt no more,</l>
               <l>These wo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ds I'll say untill I dy,</l>
               <l>I cannot love thee no not I.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>I'll give thee Gold, I'll give thee Pearl,</l>
               <l>If thou will fancie me my Girl,</l>
               <l>I'll give the House, I'll give thee Land,</l>
               <l>I'll give thee silver in thy hand.</l>
               <l>I'll give thee costly Robs to wear,</l>
               <l>That not one shall with thee compare,</l>
               <l>Then never stand to answer no,</l>
               <l>If you love me tell me so.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Its not your Gifts shall me entice</l>
               <l>To change my vertue into Vice,</l>
               <l>Nor shall that flattering tongue of thine,</l>
               <l>Inchant the settled heart of mine,</l>
               <l>I had rather go in needy rags,</l>
               <l>Then have thee with thy Golden Bags,</l>
               <l>I am resolved a Maid to dy,</l>
               <l>I cannot love thee no not I.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>If no perswasion may thee move,</l>
               <l>To change this hate and fall to Love,</l>
               <l>There is no other hopes of me,</l>
               <l>But I will die for love of thee,</l>
               <l>Then may the World both judge &amp; say</l>
               <l>That thou hast cast a Man away,</l>
               <l>To save my Life before you go,</l>
               <l>If you love me tell me so.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Suppose thou might my life command</l>
               <l>A naked Sword drawn in my hand,</l>
               <l>And that thou aimst to Pierce my heart,</l>
               <l>I sute would take it in good part,</l>
               <l>I had rather so to end my Life,</l>
               <l>Then for to yeild to be thy wife,</l>
               <l>And for my own part live or dy,</l>
               <l>I cannot love thee no not I.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Why then farewell thou scornfull dame</l>
               <l>As thou art stout I'll be the same,</l>
               <l>And as thou <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>as<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> been <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>oy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>o me,</l>
               <l>Hence for<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>h I'll do the like by thee,</l>
               <l>I make no doubt e're long to find,</l>
               <l>A love agreeing to my mind,</l>
               <l>Adieu, adieu, my unkind foe,</l>
               <l>Th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>u never more shall say me no.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Nay stay sweet love run not too fast,</l>
               <l>You make as if you were in haste.</l>
               <l>Before you go take here a Kiss,</l>
               <l>In token of a true lovers bliss.</l>
               <l>Take hand &amp; heart &amp; all that's mine</l>
               <l>Henceforth for ever shall be thine</l>
               <l>I'll be thy true and loving Wife,</l>
               <l>Whilst I possess my breath and life.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now are the bitter storms all past.</l>
               <l>Sweet crums of comfort comes at last</l>
               <l>The raging winds doth cease to blow▪</l>
               <l>And <hi>Beachus</hi> cups doth overflow,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>My</hi> Love hath tyed a true Loves knot,</l>
               <l>Her Love shall never be forgot.</l>
               <l>Though she at first did say me no</l>
               <l>She's now my own and shall be so.</l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>